<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-27T22:24:44+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aman’s Blog</title><subtitle>A collection of the articles I wrote about several of my Life Experiences, Creations, Travel Guides, and Projects.</subtitle><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><entry><title type="html">Test Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2022/04/26/test-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Blog" /><published>2022-04-26T20:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-04-26T20:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2022/04/26/test-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2022/04/26/test-blog.html">&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Installing Krita in Ubuntu 20.04 using the AppImage and creating a desktop entry</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2022/03/12/installing-krita-from-appimage-ubuntu-20_04.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Installing Krita in Ubuntu 20.04 using the AppImage and creating a desktop entry" /><published>2022-03-12T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2022-03-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2022/03/12/installing-krita-from-appimage-ubuntu-20_04</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2022/03/12/installing-krita-from-appimage-ubuntu-20_04.html">&lt;script src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/assets/js/prism.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Krita is a sketching and painting program. It is also be used for 2D animations and is considered
an free and open source alternative to Adobe Animate. Their recommended way to use Krita is to
download the App Image and run it as an executable. But this way you would have run the file from
the terminal every time you want to use it. Wouldn't it be better if we could run the app as any
other normal application! This tutorial explains how you can install Krita's AppImage (and for that
matter any AppImage) and run it like you would run any other application.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; Download Krita's AppImage from their website's download page &lt;a href=&quot;https://krita.org/en/download/krita-desktop/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Open the terminal and go to the directory where the AppImage has been downloaded &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Run &lt;code&gt; chmod +x krita.appimage &lt;/code&gt; &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Copy the AppImage to &lt;code&gt; /usr/local/bin/&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;~/.local/bin/&lt;/code&gt; using the &lt;code&gt;cp&lt;/code&gt; command. Use &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; if you get the &lt;code&gt;Permission Denied&lt;/code&gt; error. &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Change directory to the directory where the AppImage was downloaded &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Run &lt;code&gt; ./krita.appimage --appimage-extract &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; This should extract the contents of the AppImage into the directory &lt;code&gt; squashfs-root &lt;/code&gt; in the same directory &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; &lt;code&gt; cd &lt;/code&gt; into the &lt;code&gt; squashfs-root &lt;/code&gt; directory and open the file &lt;code&gt; org.kde.krita.desktop &lt;/code&gt; in a text editor for editing. &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Search for the line saying &lt;code&gt; Exec=krita %F &lt;/code&gt; and replace &lt;code&gt;krita&lt;/code&gt; with the location where you copied the AppImage. Eg. If you copied the AppImage to &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/&lt;/code&gt;, then the location of the AppImage is &lt;code&gt;/usr/local/bin/krita.appimage&lt;/code&gt;. Save changes and exit. &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Copy the modified &lt;code&gt; org.kde.krita.desktop &lt;/code&gt; file to &lt;code&gt; /.local/share/applications/ &lt;/code&gt; directory. &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; This will create a desktop entry for &lt;code&gt; Krita &lt;/code&gt; but we still need to put the desktop icon in the proper directory. &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Now copy icon file, &lt;code&gt;krita.png&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;/usr/share/pixmaps/&lt;/code&gt; using &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; Restart the GNOME shell by pressing &lt;code&gt;Alt+F2&lt;/code&gt; and Run &lt;code&gt;restart&lt;/code&gt;. You may even try restarting the computer. &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; After this the AppImage should be properly installed along with the desktop entry.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt; This approach can be followed for other AppImages as well &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Silent Patient by Alex Michaelides</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/literature/2021/10/05/book-review-the-silent-patient.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Silent Patient by Alex Michaelides" /><published>2021-10-05T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/literature/2021/10/05/book-review-the-silent-patient</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/literature/2021/10/05/book-review-the-silent-patient.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Silent patient is a psychological thriller and should I say what a thriller it is.
Besides, this was the first psychological thriller novel that I have read in my life
and it has been an amazing experience. It is approximately a three hundred page book
but it kept me hooked to it through all its chapters. This book has a mystery like no
other that I have read till now and even though many times you would think that the 
ending is very predictable while reading the book, you, my friend, will be dead wrong,
and that is what makes this book quite mind blowing. Another interesting thing that I
liked about this book is that it is like two novels written from the narrator’s
perspective but with events happening in two different timelines. The writer has quite
successfully managed to not let the reader realize this until the very end. Overall,
reading this book has been quite a new and thrilling experience for me and would
recommend it to any adult who likes reading psychological thrillers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book revolves around a talented painter Alicia who has been charged with murdering
her husband Gabriel in cold blood by shooting him 5 times in his face. She does not try
to defend herself and is found guilty of the crime based on the evidence found on the
scene of crime. Given her past history of mental illness and trauma, she is sent to a
mental institution with the name Groves instead of being imprisoned where she spends
the remaining of her days silent and heavily drugged by the therapist assigned to her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Theo, the narrator of the story and a psychactrist shows a deep interest in
this murder and wants to know the truth behind it and Alicia’s enigmatic character.
Led by this, he applies for a job in Groves institute for the position of a psychiactrist
even after being warned by his supervisor that he is committing a career suicide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching Groves he manages to convince Dr. Diomedes to let him treat Alicia who
is currently being treated by his old colleague and acquiantance Christian who only
keeps Alicia under heavy dosage of drugs. This was required because Alicia has been 
involved in violent incidences in the hospital and also never showed any interest in 
interaction or any sort of therapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, while treating Alicia, Theo talks to her relatives, neighbours, and friends 
in order to understand Alicia’s past and to understand what led her to do something 
so drastic as to murder her own husband. Soon he learns that Alicia had a pretty rough 
childhood filled with trauma and betrayals. She and her mother met with a car accident 
when she was a kid in which she survived and her mother was killed. One of the important 
revelations of the story is that her father wished that Alicia would have died instead 
of his wife which devastated her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the narrator is narrating this part of the story, the author keeps giving us a glimpse 
into Theo’s life. Theo is a married man and is deeply in love with his wife Kathy. 
One day he finds out that Kathy is cheating on him. After spying on her he is able to 
locate the guy with whom she is having an affair. Theo keeps a watch over the guy and 
his house for several days. Soon he finds out that the guy has a wife and starts 
sympathising with her and comparing the state she is in with his own. He continues to 
keep a watch over their house over several days and decides whether to tell the wife 
about her husband’s affair. One night he gets a chance to find his wife alone in the 
home as he knows that her husband is with Kathy. So, he decides to confront her and 
breaks into her home with a knife when she notices him. Theo manages to soon make her 
his hostage and talks to her till her husband arrives. At this point the reader realizes 
that the woman is actually Alicia and her husband, Gabriel, is the one having an affair 
with Kathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story ends with Theo overdozing Alicia in the mental institution as he has realized 
that Alicia has managed to recognize him as the person responsible for whatever has 
happened with Alicia. But, before Alicia has goes into a coma because of the overdose, 
she manages to write the truth behind the murder of her husband in her diary and hides 
it behind the painting that she drew of her and Theo as he hates this painting. Alicia 
tells in her diary that when Theo broke into her home on the night of the murder, he ties 
Gabriel when he arrives home and tells everything about the his and Kathy’s affair to 
Alicia. He then tells Gabriel that he is going to kill either Alicia or him and he is 
the one to choose. Alicia still thinks that Gabriel loves her and would not let her die, 
but Gabriel chooses for himself to live, quite similar to what happened in the Alcestice 
mythology, where the husband condemns his wife to die. Upon hearing his answer Theo points 
the gun at Alicia and shoots. But he shoots only at the wall and to scare them. He then 
hands the gun over to Alicia and tells her that she can do whatever she wants with Gabriel 
and leaves them. Alicia, being killed by both her father and her husband is not able to 
take this and brutally murders her husband and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years later the chief inspector visits Theo’s house with Alicia’s diary. 
Upon seeing this Theo understands that he has come to arrest him and complies without 
any struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html">Review</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Being Simple and Frugal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/lifestyle/2021/08/30/being-simple-and-frugal-001.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Being Simple and Frugal" /><published>2021-08-30T01:28:00+05:30</published><updated>2021-08-30T01:28:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/lifestyle/2021/08/30/being-simple-and-frugal-001</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/lifestyle/2021/08/30/being-simple-and-frugal-001.html">&lt;p&gt;In this series on Being Simple and Frugal I would take you through my
experiences, thoughts, and philosophy on how I lead my life with simplicity
and frugality, and how I use it to my advantage to attain financial
independence and retire early (F.I.R.E.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-philosophy&quot;&gt;My Philosophy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before I knew the concept of living frugally, my philosophy of living
life was to live it simple and frugal. Now you may want to ask me why I
would choose to do that. There were several reasons behind it, and one of
my primary reasons was that I could not see myself in fancy clothes,
having fancy food or any other fancy habits knowing that most of the
people living in India, and around the world are living in poverty who
did not even have the resources to meet their basic needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another reason which mattered to me a lot and motivated me to live
frugally was that I believe that we, as homo sapiens, who share this
planet with billions of other creatures, should be considerate in using
the shared resources available to us on earth. For this reason, I try to
use and reuse anything and everything upto and beyond its “recommended”
lifetime and repair it if it gets damaged, which btw is possible in many
more cases than what the profit hungry corporations would want us to
think. Learning to repair the stuff that you own not only builds your
skill, an asset that most people often overlook, but also saves you a lot
of money. It also helps you build your confidence and be independent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;childhood&quot;&gt;Childhood&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was a kid, my mom, an excellent manager herself, taught me the
importance of saving money. Every time I would get some cash in gift or
as pocket money, I would put it in my savings account that my mom opened
in our almirah :P and we would often buy whatever we needed from that.
As I would come to understand soon in my twenties, this was an excellent
way to enculcate a habit of managing expenses and saving money for a kid,
but a terrible method nonetheless because of inflation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;life-at-iit-kanpur&quot;&gt;Life at IIT Kanpur&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Till I finished my school, most of my expenses were being managed by my
parents, specially my mom, which did not give me enough of a chance to
manage money and my needs on my own. But, when I moved to IIT-K, I got
some room to experiment and manage my own expenses, and I must confess
that even though my overall expenditure was not even close to that of
many of my friends, I was not really budgeting and spending money in a
balanced way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general what would happen is that I left it on my parents to send me
money on their own and would rarely ask them for money or tell them that
I was out of money for which I was scolded quite often. Whenever my
parents would send me money, I would  spend most of it on eating outside
(at least by the time I was in my third year but I was more careful with
my spending prior to that). By the time I would realize that I am running
out of money, it would be too late. This usually did not affect me as I
had almost no expenses of my own other than food. All didn’t go too well
by the time I reached my fourth year as then I opened a postpaid account
with the hostel canteen, and I spent on eating in the canteen almost
everyday, and that too without much thought about how much I am spending.
Even though my food expenses were not significant compared to what I spend
in Delhi even for my basic needs, it was high compared to how much I
usually used to spend at IITK on myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiences and mistakes like these helped me after I moved out of IITK
and started living on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moving-to-delhi&quot;&gt;Moving to Delhi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest phase of my life started on 22nd of May, 2019 when I shifted to
Delhi permanently. I was excited for starting this new phase of my life as
now I was excited about managing my expenses from my own salary and start
saving for my future. When I moved to Delhi, I had already decided that I
was going to have a simple and healthy life and have control over my
spending. I started by making an initial investment to set up my kitchen
and started cooking on my own from the very first week of shifting here.
It took me a few tries to make something good, but, once I had mastered a
dish I would make it for a few weeks in a row till I got bored. Since I
used to cycle 16-17km everyday, my main focus was to cook dishes which
were full of protien and ,not to forget, were tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite often, under pressure from work and hectic life, I would go through
cycles of burnout, this would lead to deveopment of unhealthy habits like
eating outside daily, and spending money uncontrollably, which would go on
for a few days, sometimes even weeks, before things would come back to
normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me, my mantra was to save money first and spend the
remaining amount which led me to save money and only spend the money which
was left over after saving. I am quite sure that most of the people who
would be reading this article would have a similar thoughts on saving.
However, my saving habits were still not that aggressive. It took me some
time to understand that my saving habits need to be more aggressive and
that I would need to not only save money but also invest it smartly for
it to grow. We will talk more about this in future articles in this series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;future&quot;&gt;Future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am at a point where I could say that I am more disciplined about
my expenses than I was before. Many mistakes and tough times, ultimately
leading to better habits, have led me to this point where I could say that
now I am beginning to understand what it takes to live simple and also
reach financial independence. As of today I still choose to live frugally
and simply both for my philosophies and my goals and I hope that I keep
doing so in future and am able to be an example for those who share my
views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html">In this series on Being Simple and Frugal I would take you through my experiences, thoughts, and philosophy on how I lead my life with simplicity and frugality, and how I use it to my advantage to attain financial independence and retire early (F.I.R.E.).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pushing to GitHub repo from Travis CI [WIP]</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2019/04/10/pushing-to-github-from-travis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pushing to GitHub repo from Travis CI [WIP]" /><published>2019-04-10T01:28:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-04-10T01:28:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2019/04/10/pushing-to-github-from-travis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/tech/2019/04/10/pushing-to-github-from-travis.html">&lt;script src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/assets/js/prism.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Sometimes we may need to make some changes in a repository and push
it to the GitHub repository from TravisCI. An example would be to use TravisCI
to deploy a Jekyll website to github for which we can
build the website in TravisCI and push the &lt;code&gt; &amp;#95;site &lt;/code&gt;
data in the GitHub branch.

&lt;br /&gt;

The issue comes when we try to push the changes in the git repository,
which requires authorisation, which can't be entered manually in TravisCI.

&lt;br /&gt;

We can solve this issue with something called GitHub's
&lt;code&gt;Personal Access Tokens&lt;/code&gt;. Generate a &lt;code&gt;Pesonal Access Token&lt;/code&gt;
by following
&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https://help.github.com/en/articles/creating-a-personal-access-token-for-the-command-line&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;
by GitHub.

&lt;br /&gt;

While generating the token, we need to give access to the github repository.
For this, check the options shown in the image below (in black border) on the
Token generator page. This will allow the service with this token to make
changes to a repository in GitHub.

&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/img/pushing-to-github-from-Travis-CI/01-github-token-generator.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GitHub Token Generator&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; /&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;


Now we need to tell TravisCI about the token. But this GitHub token
has to be encrypted before we give it to TravisCI. To do this first
install &lt;code&gt;travis&lt;/code&gt; in your local linux machine and login to
&lt;code&gt;travis&lt;/code&gt; by using these commands:
&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;
      sudo gem install travis
      travis login
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

After this, add these lines in the &lt;code&gt;after_script&lt;/code&gt; part of your
&lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.

&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;
 after_script:
   - git config credential.helper &quot;store --file=.git/credentials&quot;
   - echo &quot;https://${GH_TOKEN}:@github.com&quot; &amp;gt; .git/credentials
   - node ./node_modules/grunt-cli/bin/grunt release
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

Now, while staying in the directory where &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; is,
run,

&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;
    travis encrypt 'GITHUB_TOKEN=&amp;lt;REPLACE-WITH-YOUR-GITHUB-PERSONAL-ACCESS-TOKEN&amp;gt;' --add
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

This will add the encrypted &lt;code&gt;Personal Access Token&lt;/code&gt; in
your &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; file.

&lt;br /&gt;

When TravisCI builds on your repo, it stores this token in the global
variable &lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;GITHUB_TOKEN&lt;/code&gt;, which you can
use to push to a particular github repository via a command which looks
something like this

&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;
    git push -f -q https://${GITHUB_TOKEN}@github.com/&amp;lt;GITHUB-USERNAME&amp;GT;/&amp;lt;GITHUB-REPO-NAME&amp;gt;.git &amp;lt;DEPLOY_BRANCH&amp;gt;
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

Note however that the command &lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;
can only be used after the variable &lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;GITHUB_TOKEN&lt;/code&gt;
has been initialised, which only happens after the commands shown in
&lt;code&gt;after_script&lt;/code&gt; section of the &lt;code&gt;.travis.yml&lt;/code&gt; has
been executed. So, any script using &lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot;&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt;
should be put after those three commands in &lt;code&gt;after_script&lt;/code&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nainital Trekking Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/travel/2019/03/23/nainital-trekking-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nainital Trekking Guide" /><published>2019-03-23T20:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-03-23T20:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/travel/2019/03/23/nainital-trekking-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/travel/2019/03/23/nainital-trekking-guide.html">&lt;p&gt;I know of a very few places around Kanpur where adventure seeking enthusiasts can leave on a Friday evening and return by Sunday or Monday morning. As it turns out, Nainital is just the place where one can visit for a day and spend the day trekking to the summits of two to three peaks around Nainital. The trek will take you through the lush green forests of Kaphal, Sal, Oak, Pine, Buruns, Deodar and Surai trees. Animals like Himalayan languor is also a very common sight and if you get lucky you might even spot deers, and if unlucky….then maybe a bear. With a good enough visibility you can have a breathtaking view of the 300 km wide snow peaked rugged mountains of the Himalayas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is a detailed account of a trip I took to Nainital which included a trek to the China Peak (highest summit around Nainital) on the first day, and a trek which included hiking to the Camel’s Back mountain, China Peak, and Snow View Peak on the second day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-nainital&quot;&gt;To Nainital&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To reach Nainital, first take a train to Lucknow Charbagh station by evening from Kanpur Central. There are trains almost every hour that will take you to Lucknow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lucknow to Kathgodam
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;15043 - Arrives Kathgodam by 0800 hrs (Su, M, W, Th, Fr from Lucknow Junction which is 100m from Lucknow Charbagh). I boarded this train and found it to be mostly empty, even in the General class coach.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;13019 - Arrives Kathgodam by 0925 hrs (Daily from Lucknow Charbagh)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After reaching Kathgodam, catch a bus to Nainital. It costs around Rs. 60/- and you will reach there in 1 hr to 1.5 hr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trek-1&quot;&gt;Trek 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This trek will take you to the top of the highest peak around Nainital, China Peak. There are two trails through which you can reach the peak. This one takes you to the summit mostly through the southern slopes of the Naina Range which also faces Nainital.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This trail is 8 km long and has an average elevation grade of about 8%.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To take this trail first follow the Mall Road to the High Court. Then take the path behind the High Court to Kilbury road. After reaching the Kilbury road, you will find a trail right across the road to your right. Hike on that trail until it intersects the Kilbury road again where you will also find a small shop where you can have something to eat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue on the trail after crossing the shop. On your way you will find multiple points from where you can have views of the Snow Peaked Himalayas and a view of the Nainital Lake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Before this trail reaches the summit, it bifurcates at a point. One trail leads straight to the summit, and another leads to a Bird Sanctuary. Take the trail on the left and with a higher gradient, to reach the summit. There is a very small board at that bifurcation indicating which trail leads to the summit, but it’s worn out and it’s difficult to decipher anything from that board. I had to try both the trails for some time to be sure of which path to ultimately take to reach the summit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The accent will take you around 4 to 5 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the top you can have a breathtaking view of Nainital and 300 km wide snow-peaked Himalayan ranges.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trek-2&quot;&gt;Trek 2:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This trek will take you first to the summit of the Camel’s Back mountain, China peak, and Snow view peak.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Camel’s Back is the second highest peak around Nainital after China peak. And it’s more challenging to climb it’s summit than China peak because of very narrow and rocky trails and dense forest, where at some places you can also lose your path if you are not careful.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This trail mostly lies on the northern slopes of the Naina range which is not inhabited by the locals and you can spot deers and monkeys roaming around. You should also be careful of bears roaming around this region. So, it’s advised not to hike alone on this trail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To reach Camel’s back peak, follow the Mall road to the path behind the High Court, and take that path to the Kilbury road as in Trek 1. After reaching Kilbury road, take a left and walk along the Kilbury road for about half a kilometer until you find the trail which will lead you to the Satyanarayan Temple. This trail is a cemented path for some distance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This trail bifurcates at the Satyanarayan Temple. One leads to the summit of the Camel’s back peak and another will lead you to the China peak. First take the trail to the Camel’s back peak, there are no more bifurcations ahead. It will take you another half an hour to reach the peak.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After reaching the Camel’s back peak, return to the bifurcation and take the trail leading to the China peak. This trail also bifurcates at a point, take the trail with the higher gradient at the bifurcation. It will take you straight to the peak. This trail meets the another trail at the peak. This is the same trail which we took to reach China peak in Trek 1.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the trail from Trek 1 to descend from China peak until you reach its first intersection with Kilbury road near the small shop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From that intersection you can directly reach the trail leading to the Snow View peak. It’s a relatively easy hike to this peak. Ask around to get specific directions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are adventure parks around this peak along with restaurants and view-points from where you can have a view of the Himalayan ranges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are many paths to descend from the Snow View peak and reach the nainital lake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are no places to eat on the way to Camel’s back peak and China peak, so, you may want to take something to eat with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-nainital-to-kanpur&quot;&gt;From Nainital to Kanpur:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can catch a bus to Kathgodam station at Nainital Bus station by 1800hrs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kathgodam to Lucknow
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;15044 - Arrives Lucknow by 0800 hrs (M, T, Th, Fr, Sat).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;13020 - Arrives Lucknow by 0800 hrs.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After this you can take any one of the frequent trains from Lucknow to Kanpur Central.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cost-and-other-info&quot;&gt;Cost and Other info:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I found that it’s easy to travel in general coach for the train journey. Specially in 15043/44 as it was not crowded and I even got a place to sleep. And since it starts from Lucknow, you can easily get a place to sit or sleep if you try. I took a yoga mat along with me for sleeping. General coaches won’t cost you more than Rs. 120 for a one-way trip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hotels around Nainital are expensive. During non-season time, a double room can cost something like Rs.600 and the same room could cost you around Rs. 1500 when Nainital is filled with tourists. If you are here just for a day then you can avoid booking a hotel which is what I did for the first day. Although, hiking with a 10kg backpack can make the trek a bit difficult. Also, I couldn’t find a Clock room in Nainital.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You should also take some medicines with you for the trip. With the help of the pharmacists at the Apollo Pharmacy (IITK) and suggestions from the internet, I took the following medicines with me - Wikoryl (relief from cold and fever symptoms), Metrogyl, Digene (anti-acid), Promethazine Theoclate Tablets (motion sickness), Azithromycin tablets (anti-biotic), ORS, moov, Framycetin skin cream, and adhesive bandages. Along with these you should also take Vaseline petroleum jelly, sunscreen, soap, and some body lotion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For food I relied on peanut butter sandwiches. Peanut butter is a rich source of energy, protein and fat. For me, two sandwiches in the morning before the hike was all I needed. After which you can have your lunch of peanut butter sandwich before descending. You can buy both peanut butter and bread at the Campus-e shop and take it along with you. I found that 400g of peanut butter and two packets of bread (with around 15 to 20 slices in each) was sufficient for a two day trip. Along with this you can take lemon and honey, or glucose with you to keep you energetic throughout the hike. If you are following these suggestions, then also bring along a spoon and a knife with you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was getting an Airtel signal strong enough for calling almost everywhere except while hiking on the northern slopes of the Nanda devi Range. Still, I wasn’t able to get a good internet speed on a 3G network anywhere in Nainital. Although, I am told by the locals that Jeo 4G works best in Nainital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html">I know of a very few places around Kanpur where adventure seeking enthusiasts can leave on a Friday evening and return by Sunday or Monday morning. As it turns out, Nainital is just the place where one can visit for a day and spend the day trekking to the summits of two to three peaks around Nainital. The trek will take you through the lush green forests of Kaphal, Sal, Oak, Pine, Buruns, Deodar and Surai trees. Animals like Himalayan languor is also a very common sight and if you get lucky you might even spot deers, and if unlucky….then maybe a bear. With a good enough visibility you can have a breathtaking view of the 300 km wide snow peaked rugged mountains of the Himalayas.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Desert, Dead, Empty, and Vast</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/a-desert-dead-empty-and-vast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Desert, Dead, Empty, and Vast" /><published>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/a-desert-dead-empty-and-vast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/a-desert-dead-empty-and-vast.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;No wind to take me home
&lt;br /&gt;I travel aimless and alone
&lt;br /&gt;wondering how long will it last
&lt;br /&gt;in a desert, dead, empty, and vast
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I remember my days of past
&lt;br /&gt;on a road, untravelled by the mass
&lt;br /&gt;today I just think of my past
&lt;br /&gt;in a desert, dead, empty, and vast
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The road was tough, long, and steep
&lt;br /&gt;nevertheless, I travelled without rest and sleep
&lt;br /&gt;I knew not I will end up here at last
&lt;br /&gt;in a desert, dead, empty, and vast
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;To a tree, was the road leading me
&lt;br /&gt;full of love and soul she was to be
&lt;br /&gt;but became a mirage without a heart
&lt;br /&gt;in a desert, dead, empty, and vast
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;A truth I learned, which tore me apart
&lt;br /&gt;that it’s all nothing, but just a mirage
&lt;br /&gt;everything vanished, at a pace so fast
&lt;br /&gt;and left a desert, dead, empty, and vast
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;today I am left with an empty heart
&lt;br /&gt;searching for a road, wind, or a star
&lt;br /&gt;that takes me home where I find a heart
&lt;br /&gt;and not a desert, dead, empty, and vast&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html">No wind to take me home I travel aimless and alone wondering how long will it last in a desert, dead, empty, and vast I remember my days of past on a road, untravelled by the mass today I just think of my past in a desert, dead, empty, and vast The road was tough, long, and steep nevertheless, I travelled without rest and sleep I knew not I will end up here at last in a desert, dead, empty, and vast To a tree, was the road leading me full of love and soul she was to be but became a mirage without a heart in a desert, dead, empty, and vast A truth I learned, which tore me apart that it’s all nothing, but just a mirage everything vanished, at a pace so fast and left a desert, dead, empty, and vast today I am left with an empty heart searching for a road, wind, or a star that takes me home where I find a heart and not a desert, dead, empty, and vast</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Thin Sheet of Ice</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/a-thin-sheet-of-ice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Thin Sheet of Ice" /><published>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/a-thin-sheet-of-ice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/a-thin-sheet-of-ice.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On a foggy day
&lt;br /&gt;sight ends a fathom away
&lt;br /&gt;no lights to guide
&lt;br /&gt;I stand on a sheet of ice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I search for a rope
&lt;br /&gt;O any sign! A ray of hope
&lt;br /&gt;but in vain my effort lies
&lt;br /&gt;I stand on a sheet of ice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I think to move in ways more than a dozen
&lt;br /&gt;but help me, god! My legs are frozen
&lt;br /&gt;I cannot move whatever I try
&lt;br /&gt;I stand frozen on a sheet of ice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;In the darkness of the night
&lt;br /&gt;my heart pounds, I stand in fright
&lt;br /&gt;It becomes harder to breathe as time passes by
&lt;br /&gt;I stand frozen on a sheet of ice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I look down at the ice
&lt;br /&gt;it is thin but I see a light
&lt;br /&gt;covered in darkness, deep down it lies
&lt;br /&gt;a shining star beneath this sheet of ice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;It is my only hope
&lt;br /&gt;anywhere else I do not see even the thinnest rope
&lt;br /&gt;and hence I decide to take a dive
&lt;br /&gt;bidding a farewell to the world above the ice
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;I plunged inside and began to stroke
&lt;br /&gt;towards the light, my source of hope
&lt;br /&gt;the world seemed calm, a darkness descended
&lt;br /&gt;I had a smile, my pain has ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html">On a foggy day sight ends a fathom away no lights to guide I stand on a sheet of ice I search for a rope O any sign! A ray of hope but in vain my effort lies I stand on a sheet of ice I think to move in ways more than a dozen but help me, god! My legs are frozen I cannot move whatever I try I stand frozen on a sheet of ice In the darkness of the night my heart pounds, I stand in fright It becomes harder to breathe as time passes by I stand frozen on a sheet of ice I look down at the ice it is thin but I see a light covered in darkness, deep down it lies a shining star beneath this sheet of ice It is my only hope anywhere else I do not see even the thinnest rope and hence I decide to take a dive bidding a farewell to the world above the ice I plunged inside and began to stroke towards the light, my source of hope the world seemed calm, a darkness descended I had a smile, my pain has ended.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Song</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/my-song.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Song" /><published>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/my-song</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/my-song.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Long have I longed
&lt;br /&gt;to sing a song
&lt;br /&gt;it is my tale
&lt;br /&gt;before I grew cold and pale
&lt;br /&gt;the story of my life
&lt;br /&gt;colourful and bright
&lt;br /&gt;over the peaks I flew
&lt;br /&gt;where I saw only a few
&lt;br /&gt;a darkness I didn’t foresee
&lt;br /&gt;like a basilisk, it swallowed me
&lt;br /&gt;I went numb, and I fell
&lt;br /&gt;to a city, with a story to tell
&lt;br /&gt;I sang until I had my breath
&lt;br /&gt;but it fell on ears that were deaf
&lt;br /&gt;still as a stone, silent as the grave now I lie
&lt;br /&gt;without a light, just waiting to die&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html">Long have I longed to sing a song it is my tale before I grew cold and pale the story of my life colourful and bright over the peaks I flew where I saw only a few a darkness I didn’t foresee like a basilisk, it swallowed me I went numb, and I fell to a city, with a story to tell I sang until I had my breath but it fell on ears that were deaf still as a stone, silent as the grave now I lie without a light, just waiting to die</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We Travel Alone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/we-travel-alone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Travel Alone" /><published>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2019-01-01T04:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/we-travel-alone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/poetry/2019/01/01/we-travel-alone.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;On a dim lighted boat
&lt;br /&gt;painted in a coat
&lt;br /&gt;of dirt and soot
&lt;br /&gt;we set afoot
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;The journey is one
&lt;br /&gt;destination is the sun
&lt;br /&gt;lifeless we sit around
&lt;br /&gt;without a stir or any sound
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Eyeballs kiss
&lt;br /&gt;a moment of bliss
&lt;br /&gt;only to stir away
&lt;br /&gt;like the pendulums sway
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;Surrounded by souls
&lt;br /&gt;still, not a whole
&lt;br /&gt;your journey is your own
&lt;br /&gt;you only travel alone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    /**
     *  RECOMMENDED CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT AND UNCOMMENT THE SECTION BELOW TO INSERT DYNAMIC VALUES FROM YOUR PLATFORM OR CMS.
     *  LEARN WHY DEFINING THESE VARIABLES IS IMPORTANT: https://disqus.com/admin/universalcode/#configuration-variables
     */
    /*
    var disqus_config = function () {
        this.page.url = PAGE_URL;  // Replace PAGE_URL with your page's canonical URL variable
        this.page.identifier = PAGE_IDENTIFIER; // Replace PAGE_IDENTIFIER with your page's unique identifier variable
    };
    */
    (function() {  // REQUIRED CONFIGURATION VARIABLE: EDIT THE SHORTNAME BELOW
        var d = document, s = d.createElement('script');

        s.src = 'https://amanabt.disqus.com/embed.js';  // IMPORTANT: Replace EXAMPLE with your forum shortname!

        s.setAttribute('data-timestamp', +new Date());
        (d.head || d.body).appendChild(s);
    })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;noscript&gt;Please enable JavaScript to view the &lt;a href=&quot;https://disqus.com/?ref_noscript&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;</content><author><name>Aman Abhishek Tiwari</name></author><summary type="html">On a dim lighted boat painted in a coat of dirt and soot we set afoot The journey is one destination is the sun lifeless we sit around without a stir or any sound Eyeballs kiss a moment of bliss only to stir away like the pendulums sway Surrounded by souls still, not a whole your journey is your own you only travel alone</summary></entry></feed>